MUHAMMAD ZEESHAN

zee.1mughal@gmail.com

Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Tel: +92-301-337-0834 🛂



Social Media: fin



IOS ENGINEER

An enthusiastic and dedicated software engineer with over 4 years of experience in the mobile application field. Extremely organized with the ability to work both independently of own initiative or as part of a successful team, demonstrating the motivation and multi-tasking abilities required to meet demanding deadlines while maintaining the highest of standards. Currently looking for a new and challenging position as IOS application developer where I can showcase my experience on foreign industry.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IOS Engineer

SOFIT Consultancy (Private) Limited, Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Jul, 2021 – Present

SCPL is a global Digital Services Provider impacting millions through its technical capabilities.

Currently working on some client's projects. My main responsibilities are as follows:

- Write, modify, integrate and test IOS (swift).
- Fluent experience with SwiftUI using clean architecture.
- Write Unit and UI Test Cases.
- Identify and communicate technical problems, processes and solutions.

IOS Developer

Translation Empire, Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Mar, 2020 - May 2021

Translation Empire providing a high-quality interpreting and translation services for all over UK.

Worked on company's core applications where a customer/interpreter/professional place bookings for interpretation and translation. My main responsibilities are as follows:

- Write, modify, integrate and test IOS (swift).
- Identify and communicate technical problems, processes and solutions.
- Assist in the collection and documentation of user's requirements.
- Maintain existing applications by making modifications as required.
- Publishing applications on App Store.

Further, I have converted the old LENET Android and IOS application to a whole new look with new features.

Mobile Application Developer

Alberuni Tech, Islamabad, Pakistan

Jun, 2018 – Nov, 2019

Alberuni Tech providing IT services to national and international customers.

Worked with different teams (UI/UX Team, API, Marketing, End Users) to move the product on correct direction. Worked on both android and iOS platforms. My main responsibilities are as follows:

- Assist in the collection and documentation of user's requirements.
- Making Paper Prototypes/Wireframes or Mock-ups on Low fidelity Software (Balsamiq)
- Development (Coding + UI)
- **Testing & Bugs Fixing**
- Deployment on Store (App Store or Play store)

Further, I made company to win a project of World Bank Group worth approx. 40,000 CAD.

EXPERIENCED IN

Platforms Android, IOS

Tools (IDE) Android Studio, XCode

Languages Worked in Java, Kotlin, Swift, C#

Database MS SQL, MySQL, SQL Lite, Firebase Realtime Database

iOS Architecture Patterns MVC & MVVM

iOS Technologies UIKit, Core Graphics, Core Animation, Core Data

APIs Experience in VoIP, RESTful API, Web API, Payment APIs, Maps APIs, Social media APIs, Weather APIs

Firebase Products Authentication, Realtime Database, Storage, Cloud Storage, Notifications, Ad mob,

Crashlytics

SKILLS

- Have good written, oral and interpersonal communication skills.
- Well organized and dedicated with positive attitude.
- Discuss and present application/software.
- Ability to work under pressure.
- Time Management.
- Team Player.

PROJECTS COMPLETED AS FREELANCER

Food Jar

A stock management application where user can buy bulks of products from a stock dealer.

Technoid

An application for IT asset management and disposition solutions

Coin Budget

A budget management application that allows user to manage their monthly expenses.

• Cattle Herd

A veterinary application where user can buy/sell their cattle e.g., goat, cow, camel, sheep, buffalo. User can also search nearby veterinary hospitals through google maps.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Science in Software Engineering

Jun, 2018

National University of Modern Language, Islamabad, Pakistan

Project Washouse – Application to provide booking services to customer to wash fabrics Runner-

up at Open House Competition Held at University.

LANGUAGES

English (Read, write, understand and speak)Urdu (Read, write, understand and speak)

Punjabi (Understand and speak)

EXTRA CURRICULARS

- Traveler
- · Table Tennis
- PC-Gamer